An intruder!
-くせ者ー！
-はあっ！ あっ
It's an intruder!
An intruder has broken in!
くせ者だー！ くせ者が侵入したぞー！
That way!
-くせ者？
-あっちだ！
Don't let 'em get away!
あっ あーは！ うっ
This is why I said it'd never work!
だから無理だって
言ったのにぃー！ ひいっ
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空 果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に 充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼（はね）を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ 行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから 一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
First Battle
There! Don't let him get away!
-いたぞー！ 逃がすなあー！
-わあー！ ああっ うう！
-やあっ！
-うっ ひい！ ひっ
He's headed towards the king's chambers!
禁裏の方へ向かったぞー！
Follow him!
追え 追えー！
うわあー！ はっ　クーヤ様ぁー
Oh, Kuuya-sama!
This is too much for me after all!
やっぱり あたしには無理ですよおー！
Kuuya?
クーヤ？ クーヤがどうした
What about Kuuya?
ひゃーああっ！ ひいっ！ うっ
うっ く… あーああ
Your Highness, are you there!?
聖上 おられますか！ 聖上！
Your Highness!
どうした
What is it?
I'm sorry to disturb you, but an
intruder came in this direction.
お騒がせして申し訳ありません
賊が侵入し こちらの方へ
An intruder?
賊だと？
Come to think of it, I thought I heard
a noise coming from that direction.
そういえば 向こうの方で音がしたような
That way!
向こうだ！
ふひいっ！
There is no need to fear.
怖がらなくていい
You are you Kuuya's servant, right?
お前はクーヤの使いなのだろ？
Huh?
もしかして ハクオロ様でありますか？
Could you be Hakuoro-sama?
I'm... I mean, my name is Sakuya.
あたし… じゃなくて
自分の名はサクヤであります
By order of Her Highness Kuuya Amrulineulka,
I have come to...
アムルリネウルカ・クーヤ様の命により
お迎えにつかまつか… くっ ぎっ うう…
ああ　今日はゲンジマルではないのだな
So, no Genjimaru today?
Grandpa... I mean, Tauro is, well...
おじいちゃ… じゃなくて
大老（タゥロ）は
ちょっとその 色々と…
You are Genjimaru's grandchild?
そなたはゲンジマルの孫なのか
Yes!
I'm surprised you got this far,
as small and delicate as you are.
そんな華奢な体で
よく ここまで潜り込めたものだ
うっう ひっ… うう
ひっ ああー　はっはああー！
はあっ うーうっ うう…
You're late! I've grown weary from waiting!
遅い　待ちくたびれたぞ
My apologies! My apologies!
あっ すみません すみません
Sakuya, you don't need to apologize.
サクヤが謝るでない
Hakuoro's the one at fault!
悪いのはハクオロだ
は？ 私のせいなのか？
So this is my fault?
By the way, Sakuya, what happened to your hair?
それにしてもサクヤ その髪はどうした？
The beautiful hair that used to
come down to your waist?
あの腰まであった美しい髪だ
What's the matter? Sakuya?
どうしたのだ サクヤ？
うっう ふうっ うう いーいい…
ひいっ うっ ひい ううう… ぐっ
ふん
So, what is it this time?
それで？ 今日はどうした
I wanted to continue with what
we were discussing earlier.
以前話したことを
進めておこうと思ってな
うん？ 何の話だ
What was that?
About you taking a wife from my country.
そなたが我が国から
室を迎えるという話だ
A wife!?
室？ うわあっ！
Who's there?
うっ 誰？
Eruruu?
エルルゥ
Queen Amrulineulka of Kunekamun?
クンネカムンのアムルリネウルカンホ？
I'm telling you that you needn't worry.
だから心配はいらぬ
Hakuoro and I are not involved in
the way you think we are.
ハクオロと余は そなたが
思っているような仲ではない
I... I didn't really think you were.
べ 別に私はそんなこと…
Then why were you eavesdropping?
ならば なぜ盗み見などしておった
あっ はあ　だから それはその…
Well, it was because....
Well, no matter.
まあ よい
More importantly, about getting a wife for you...
それより室の話だ
余はサクヤを
ハクオロの室にと思っている
I was thinking of Sakuya as a wife for Hakuoro.
What!?
えーええっ！ そんなこと聞いてないです
I haven't heard anything about this!
うん 言ってない
Right, I never mentioned it.
How about it, Hakuoro?
どうだ ハクオロ
You won't find a prettier, or harder
working girl than Sakuya.
サクヤほどの働き者の器量よし
他には そうおらんぞ
On top of that, she's great in bed!
しかも 床上手だ
G... Great in bed!?
とっ 床上手？
あーあ あああ…
あーの クク クーヤ様？
Uh, umm...
Kuuya-sama!?
Yes, when Sakuya does my bedding,
I'm able to sleep very well.
うん　サクヤが寝床を整えてくれると
とてもよく眠れるのだ
はっ クーヤ その床上手は意味が違うぞ
Kuuya, that is not what "great in bed" means.
It's not?
違う？
ふんっ ふんっ
Then what does it mean?
では どういう意味なのだ？
Well, uh...
それは その…
Oh, well, no matter.
まあ よい
-で どうなのだ？
-あっ
So, what do you think?
Sakuya is also my precious friend.
サクヤは余にとって大切な友である
Therefore, I wish her to be happy.
なればこそ サクヤには
幸せになってもらいたい
So, I thought rather than just being a retainer,
she could be your wife.
そこで余の付き人などではなく
そなたの室へ入れたいと思ったのだ
うっ　しかしサクヤがいなくなったら
But wouldn't you be inconvenienced
with Sakuya gone?
クーヤは困らないのか？
Oh, that's right...
あ！ そうであった
Sorry, let me think this one over.
すまぬ　この話は今一度 考えさせてくれ
Hakuoro, I'm glad I could see you tonight.
ハクオロ
今日は そなたに会えてよかった
I don't think I'll be able to
see you again for a while.
しばらく会えそうにないのでな
Some who bear ill will towards Kunekamun have
been engaged in some disturbing activities of late.
我らクンネカムンに
よこしまな思いを持つ輩が
きな臭い動きをしておる
War may break out before long.
近々 戦になるやもしれん
War?
戦に？
あ… ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
Don't you fret.
そんな顔をするでない
There is no way my country of
Kunekamun shall be defeated.
余のクンネカムンは
万が一にも負けはせぬ
However, I do appreciate your concern.
だが
そなたの気持ち 嬉しく思うぞ
クーヤさん
Kuuya-san...
Here is the report.
ご報告申し上げます
We believe that Elemui is making an
advance towards Kunekamun.
クンネカムンに攻め込もうと
動いているのは
エルムイと思われます
Elemui?
エルムイ？
It is a league of several smaller nations.
小さな部族が
いくつか集まっただけの小國です
But I am concerned with the movement
of their ally, Nosecheska.
ただ 気になるのはエルムイと
同盟関係にある ノセシェチカの動き
One of the Three Great Kingdoms?
三大強國の１つか
Yes!
はい
Kunekamun will not stand a chance if
it is attacked by Nosecheska.
クンネカムンも
ノセシェチカに攻め込まれては
ひとたまりもないか
I wonder about that.
それはどうでしょう
It is said that Kunekamun possesses
an unknown power.
クンネカムンには 得体の知れない
力があると言われています
An unknown power?
得体の知れない 力か
Brother!
兄者！
Camus sucked her blood?
カミュが血を？
Aruruu...
アルルゥ
Sister...
お姉ちゃん…
Are you all right?
大丈夫
Yeah...
Camus...
カミュ…
Father, where's Camus-cchi?
お父さん
カミュちーは？
She'll be all right.
ああ 大丈夫だ
Let's just find her, quickly.
とにかく早く カミュを見つけよう
Right!
I'll help look for her too.
アルルゥも捜しに行く
Aruruu?
アルルゥ
I'm gonna help find Camus too!
アルルゥもカミュちー捜す
Gachatara!
ガチャタラ
Aruruu, wait!
アルルゥ 待ちなさい！
Yuzuha, you go back to your room.
ユズハ お前は部屋に戻ってろ
I'll wait.
待ってる
I will wait here until Camus-chan is found.
カミュちゃんが見つかるまで
ここで待ってる
Yuzuha-chan...
ユズハちゃん
Camus!
カミュー！
Camus...
カミュ
We have been looking for you.
捜したぞ
Mister...
おじ様　ふっ ふっ…
ふふーう ふっ ふっ ふっ
ひっ ひっ ふふぅふ…
ひぃっ　カミュね カミュ 皆と違うんだ
I... I'm different from everyone else!
カミュ１人だけ真っ黒な翼で
I'm the only one with jet-black wings.
I'm the only one who's different!
カミュ１人だけ違うの　ふっ ふっ
They say these black wings are the sign of a
strong blood connection with our great ancestor.
この黒い翼って
偉大な始祖様の血を
強く受け継いでいる証なんだって…
ひっ　それで どこでも特別扱いされて
So, I've always been treated
differently wherever I went,
and everyone's always wary of me.
皆よそよそしくって
I never had any friends until I came here.
カミュ ここに来るまで
お友達いなかったの　ふうっ ふっ
I don't want these dark wings.
カミュ こんな黒い翼 嫌だ！
If only I had white wings like my sister,
お姉様みたいな真っ白な翼だったら
then what I did wouldn't have happened!
カミュ あんなことしなかったよ
うふっ ふうっ
I don't want Aru-chan to hate me!
やだよお アルちゃんに嫌われたくない
ひっ　初めてのお友達なの！ 本当の
She was my very first friend!
My first true friend!
初めての友達なの…
ひいっ うう…
ふっ　大丈夫だ
It's okay.
Do you think Aruruu would be bothered
by something like that?
アルルゥが あれぐらいのことを
気にするはずがないだろう
But...
でも…
I found Camus-cchi.
-カミュちー見つけた
-ああっ
Everyone was worried about you, Camus.
皆カミュのことを心配していたんだ
Because we're your friends.
友達だからな
My friends?
友達…
ふーん　カミュちー みーっけ！
I found you!
We're back, Yuzu-cchi.
ただいま ユズっち
Welcome back, Aru-chan, Camu-chan.
おかえりなさい
アルちゃん カミュちゃん
んっ んっ ひいっ
うわあー　はっはっは
うぅはっはあー！
うふっ うふっ うう… うああー！
うふっ うふっ うっ うああー！ ふっ うふっ
うふっ うふっ ひい あーあっ…
What?
何？
エルムイがクンネカムンに侵攻？
Elemui is invading Kunekamun!?
Yes, Nosecheska is sending its troops to Elemui.
はい
ノセシェチカもエルムイに
進軍を開始したようです
So, it has started...
始まったか
Kuuya-san...
クーヤさん…
Let's go! We'll trample and crush those
filthy Kunekamun insects!
行くぞおー！
クンネカムンのクソ虫どもを
ひねり潰せええー！
My Lord, what's that!?
聖上！ ああ あれは…
What is that thing?
何だ あれは？
Now is the time to show the world what
happens to those who defy us!
我らに牙を剥けば どうなるか
今こそ世に示す時！
Let's go!
行くぞおっ！
Roger!
御意！
Don't let them deceive you!
うろたえるなあ！ あんなもの
クソ虫どものハッタリよ！
This is just some sort of ruse those
filthy insects have come up with!
ぎっ いっ 参る！
En guarde!
うおおっ うぉわああ！
It's just for sho...
ハッタリ…
はははは…！ はっはっはっ…！
逃げろ 逃げろー！
Run, run!
Those... those filthy insects, they...
クソ虫が… クソ虫があっ！
Filthy insect?
クソ虫は
Looks like that's what you've turned out to be!
あんただったようだねえ
うわああー！ わあっ わあっ！
あっ わああー！ うっ わああーっ！
My army's been defeated by these filthy insects?
俺様が… クソ虫どもに 負ける？
No way... There's no way I'll stand for this!
バカな… そんなバカなことが
あってたまるかああー！
I will not be defeated!
俺様が負けなどおおー！
Kunekamun shall not be defeated!
クンネカムンは負けはせん！
うっ あっ あっ　ははあ　あ…
A man died, by my hands...
人が死んだ 余の 手で…
うう うわっ　わああ！ 走れえ！
Your Highness, please get a hold of yourself!
聖上 お心を しっかりお持ちください
Going too easy on them will
only earn us their scorn.
つまらぬ情けは怨恨を生む
Inform all the troops!
全軍に伝えよ！
We shall continue our advance!
このまま進軍する！
They surrendered?
陥落？
The great Nosecheska was brought
down in only three days!?
あのノセシェチカが たった３日で？
Hakuoro-sama, I have come to escort you.
ハクオロ様　お迎えに参りました
Avu Kamu...
アブ・カムゥ
This is the great power bestowed
upon us by Onvitaikayan.
オンヴィタイカヤンから授かった
大いなる力だ
So, this is the power of Kunekamun...
これが クンネカムンの力
It's been a while, Hakuoro.
久しいな ハクオロ
I am pleased to see you again.
また会えて嬉しく思うぞ
Likewise.
私もだ
I heard about the war.
戦のことは聞いた
うっふ　だから言ったであろう
That's why I told you that Kunekamun
would not be defeated!
クンネカムンに敗北は無いと
Ah, that's right!
あっ　そうだ
Let me tell you all about how I
thwarted the invasion!
そなたに聞かせてやろう
余が先鋒を駆けるさまを
It was none other than I who slew Kanholdari!
何を隠そう カンホルダリを
倒したのは この余である
It was a spectacular blow.
まさに見事な一刀であった
How feeble a country becomes without its king!
皇(オゥルォ)を失った國など
脆いものだな
We scattered the defeated troops, then without
missing a beat, we marched into Nosecheska.
敗走する敵兵を蹴散らし
余は怯むことなく
ノセシェチカへと攻め入った
ふっふふ　何が三大強國だ
What a joke! The Three Great Kingdoms...
What's the use of military might
in the hands of men?
たかが人の手による武力が何になる
Were they planning to stop the
Avu Kamu with their screams?
悲鳴でアブ・カムゥを
止めるとでもいうのか
I wish I could have shown you how my army
took out one fort after another,
そなたにも見せてやりたかったぞ
余の軍が次々と
敵の集落を制圧するさまを
and the strength of the Avu Kamu!
アブ・カムゥの力を！
Enough, Kuuya.
もういい クーヤ
What? I was just about to get to
the good part of the story...
な 何だ　話の腰を折るでない
ここからが…
That's enough.
もういいんだ
You can tell, can't you?
そなたには分かるのだな
You know that was my first battle.
初陣であったのだ
That feeling...
感触が
The feeling of slaying a man...
人を斬った あの感触が
The blood stains won't come off.
血が こびりついて離れない
I took the lives of my enemies, and
I took the lives of their people.
敵の命を奪い 民の命を奪い
I manipulated people as if they
were pawns in a game.
そして 命を駒のように操る
I learned how difficult that is,
それが どんなにつらいことか
and what a heavy burden it is to
command an army at war.
戦で上に立つ者の重責がどんなものか
You are indeed a strange man.
そなたは不思議な男だな
Look at how you've managed
to get past my defenses.
余を こんなにも無防備にする
I've never felt this way before.
こんな気持ちは初めてだ
Please help us! We were coerced by Kanholdari!
お お助けください
全てはカンホルダリに
脅されてやったこと
We had no intentions of attacking Kunekamun!
わたくし達にクンネカムンを
攻める意思など無かったのです
Please, please...
どうか どうか
ハクオロ様のお口添えを…
Hakuoro-sama, please speak
to them on our behalf!
Urutori...
ウルトリィ
Yes...
はい
Please rise, Lord Ponahoi.
お立ちください　ポナホイ殿
I don't know how much help I can be,
but I will assist you.
どこまで お力になれるか分かりませんが
わたくしが使者に立ちましょう
はっ ははあ あっ！
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much!
So does this mean that anything is permissible
if one is coerced into doing it?
だったら何かい？
脅されたのなら
何をやってもいいってのか
I understand your anger,
お怒りになるのは ごもっともです
however, in the spirit of mercy,
won't you forgive him?
ですが 慈悲の心を持って
許して差し上げる
わけにはまいりませんか？
I'm sure even our god Witsalnemitea
would not desire any more wars.
これ以上の争いは
大神(オンカミ)
ウィツァルネミテアも望まないでしょう
ふっははは…！
Witsalnemitea wouldn't desire any more wars?
ウィツァルネミテアが
争いを望まないだって？
Hatred, fighting, killing...
憎しみ 戦い 殺し合うことを教えた神が
Why wouldn't the god that taught
those things desire more war?
どうして争いを望まないっていうんだい
That's...
それは…
Besides, to us, Witsalnemitea
is the God of Misfortune.
大体 僕達にとって
ウィツァルネミテアなんてのは
ヌグィソムカミでしかないんだよ
And you think we're going to listen to
a clan that worships such a god?
それを崇拝する輩の話を
聞けると思っているのかい
Then you won't concede this point
no matter what?
どうしても分かっては
頂けないのですか？
We need the other countries to know
what happens to those who defy us.
我が國に牙を剥いた者達がどうなるか
他國にも知っておいてもらわないと
いけないからねえ
Excuse me.
失礼
Please relay this message to
the Queen Amrulineulka!
アムルリネウルカホに
お取次ぎください！
I have been left in complete
charge of this situation.
この件は全て僕が任されているんだ
So when I speak, I speak for Her Highness.
僕の言葉は 聖上の言葉なんだよ
ふっふ はっははは…！
はっはははは！ はははは…！
How's it going?
守備はどうだい？
Must be a challenge to fix something
as broken as this is.
これだけ壊れていれば
いじりがいもあるだろう？
You do understand, right?
分かってるよねえ
If it can't move on its own,
you have to make it move.
動かないなら
動かしてあげればいいんだってこと
Make it fun, very fun...
楽しく 楽しくね
ふっふふ ふっはははは
ふっはははは！ ふっははは…！
Is there going to be more war now?
また戦が始まるんですか
Can't you talk to Kuuya-san and put a stop to this?
ハクオロさんからクーヤさんに話して
止められませんか？
Kuuya is well aware of it.
クーヤは十分に分かっている
What I am worried about is...
ただ 心配なのは
I'm here to report.
ご報告申し上げます
Kunekamun has invaded Elemui.
クンネカムンがエルムイに侵攻しました
Hakuoro-san!
ハクオロさん
So, it has finally begun...
とうとう始まったか
炎さえも凍てついた
honou sae mo itetsuita
I seek the solitude
kokuno naka moto mu
that freezes even flames.
孤独の中求む
魂から結びつき 私を恋い温めて
tamashi kara musubitsuki
Connecting with your soul,
watashi wo koi atatamete
warm me with your love.
嗚呼 祈りの言葉がふるえ
a inori no kotoba ga furue
Ah...the words of prayer tremble...
嗚呼 弱きいのちが消えても
a yowaki no chika kiete mo
Ah even if the faint-hearted
were to disappear...
くりかえす 輪廻の流れ辿り
kurikaesu innen no nagare tadori
Following the recurring paths of fate.
終わらない世界の宿命を見つめてる
owaranai sekai no shukumei wo mitsumeteru
I gaze upon the never-ending world's destiny.
くりかえし 詠われる者達よ
kurikaeshi utawareru mono tachi yo
Oh the ones being sung continuously
守られてまどろむ宵
mamorarete madoromu you ni
be protected and sleep.
The Great Seal